Guide to the Resource Center for Women and Ministry in the South Records, 1939-2018 RL.01081
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2011-0146), 2007-2011, 3 boxes
  - Events (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 1)
    - Barcelona and Montserrat Trip, 2008 Apr. 26-May (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Writing Week, 2008 May (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Beach Weekend, 2008 June 13-15 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Meeting with Holy Ground, MM Place, Laura Collins, and Maggie Henry, 2008 June 21 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Writing Week 709, 2008 July 17-23 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Yoga in the Park, 2008 Summer (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Labor Day with Jean O'Barr, 2008 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Traces of our Trade, 2008 Sept. 6 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Meditation with Therese, 2008 Sept. 18-21 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Writing Week, 2008 Sept. 26-Oct. 3 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Duke Convocation, 2008 Oct. 13-15 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Bryant and Bookmaking, 2008 Oct. 14, 21, and 28 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - North Carolina Center for Nonprofits, 2008 Oct. 15-17, 2008 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 2)
    - Wise Choices, 2008 Oct. 16-19 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Dismantling Racism, 2008 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Sallie Bingham Center at Duke 20th Anniversary Celebration, 2008 Oct. 30-31 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Art Walk, 2008 Nov. 9 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Marie Fortune at Duke Divinity School, 2008 Nov. 12 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Sounds of Silence, 2008 Dec. (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Interfaith Celebration, 2008 Dec. (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Dances of Universal Peace, 2008 Dec. 31 (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
    - Switzerland Trip, 2009 Spring (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
  - AFD Artists List (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
  - Email Calendar, 2010 Aug.-2011 Jul. (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
  - Mailings (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
  - Kilgore, Nancy. Sea Level: A Novel. Durham: RCWMS, 2011. (Box Acc. 11/146: Box 3)
  - South of the Garden, 2010 Sept.-2011 Jun. (Box Acc. 11/146: Oversize Folder 1)
- Accession (2012-0155), 2009-2012, 1 box
  Accession predominately consists of handouts, organization and registration information for workshops, conventions, and retreats.
  - Interfaith, 2009 Dec. 20 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Book Fair, 2009 Nov. 15 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Anita McLeod's 70th birthday party, 2009 Nov. 7 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Jean O'Barr Symposium, 2009 Oct. 30 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Liz Dowling Sendor- Writing From Your Wounds, 2009 Oct. 14- Nov. 4 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Crone's Counsel, 2009 Oct. 21-25 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Wise Choices, cancelled (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Writing Week, 2009 Sept. 20-27 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Book Tea, 2009 Sept. 18 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Jenny Gaves Inter-generational Writing Group, 2009 June (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Beach Retreat, 2009 June 12-14 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Tibbie's 95th birthday party, 2009 May 9 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Writing Week, 2009 May 10-17 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Temple of the Goddess, 2009 May 9 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Binkley Church, 2009 Apr. 2-10 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Wise Choices, 2009 Apr. 30-May 3 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Civil Rights, 2009 Apr. 2-4 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Carol Henderson, 2009 Mar. 27-28 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Labyrinth Duke, 2009 Mar. 24 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Farmworker Institute, 2009 Apr. 14 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - NC Council Legislative Seminar- Farmworkers, 2009 Mar. 31 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Holy Ground, 2009 Mar. 5 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Phyllis Trible Lecture Series, 2009 Mar. 3-4 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Sue Sneddon Art Workshop, 2009 Feb. 19-22 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - St. Giles Church, 2009 Feb. 1 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - St. Matthews Hillsborough, Jan. 18 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Writing Week, 2009 Jan. 4-11 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - NC Center Nonprofits, 2009 Sept. 10-11 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - SAF Nomination, 2010 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Yoga in the Park, 2009 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Jane Hoover Writing Workshop, 2009 Aug. 28-29 (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Original Meinrad Project (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - South of the Garden Newsletter, 2012 June (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
  - Calendar of RCWMS events and other events of interest, 2012 July (Box Acc. 12/155: Box 1)
- Accession (2014-0187), 1996-2012; 2 boxes; Accession constists of event and project files, 1986-2012; printed email calendars, 2012-2013; correspondence, 1988-2012; resource files (films and music), and oversized posters.
  - Event and project files, printed email calendars, correspondence, and resource files, 1986-2012 (Box 11)
  - Posters (Box 12)
- Accession (2015-0081), 2000-2015; 1 boxes; Addition constists of Center newsletters, calendars, mailings, program and project files, 2000-2015
  - Newsletters, calendars, mailings, program and project files, 2000-2015 (Box 12)
- Accession (2018-0116), 1978-2018; 5 boxes; This accession consists of materials related to the life of Sister Evelyn Mattern (1941-2003), a Roman Catholic nun who worked for social justice in North Carolina.
  - Evelyn Mattern from Mel Williams Materials, 1995-2004 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Evelyn Mattern Materials related to NC Council of Churches, 2003-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Evelyn Mattern Sermon by Mel Williams, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Materials from the NC Council of Churches, 1988-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Evelyn Mattern: File of Claudia Horwitz, 1997-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Evelyn Mattern: From the File of Collins Killburn and Martha Hamilton, 1988-2011 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - South of the Garden issues, 2016-2017 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 5)
  - Email Calendar, 2015-2017 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Postcards/Holiday Greeting Cards, 2015-2018 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Meinrad Craighead- Archives, 2003-2009 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - History- Women, 1978-1986 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Interfaith Celebration, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Quiet Day, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Book Sale, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Carolyn Toben = Reading, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - KDI Participants, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - RCWMS 35th Ann. Notes, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - KDI- 35th Ann., 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 1)
  - Cancelled Workshop: Write to the Soul in the Desert, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Ann Koppleman Workshop, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Nancy Poling workshop, 2010-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Homegrown: NC Women Preaching, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - WW Pelican House, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Grandmothers Speak, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - RCWMS B'day, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - NC Center for Nonprofits, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Harvesting Our Stories, 2011-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Kathe Schaaf, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Writing Week, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - NC A-1 Amendment, 2008-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Legacy Planning for Women, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Sallie Bingham Center Symposium, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Jane Redmont Guilford College, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Carol Eckerman, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Holy Week, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Carol Henderson, 2011-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Japanese Tea, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Lynne Hinton New Mexico, 2011 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Rita Nakashima Brock Cancelled, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Labyrinth Duke Chapel, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Mindful Writing, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Duke Women, 2010-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Clergy Women Preparing for Lent, 2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Sue Sneddon, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - End of Life Series, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Peggy Payne, 2003-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Writing Week, 2011-2012 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Interfaith 2014 - 20th Anniversary, 2012-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Writing in the Dark Rebecca Welper, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Ann Loomis Reading, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Carol Woods JS talk on Labyrinth, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Betty Wolfe Stage, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Anita & Sherylyn Herons Walk, 2014-2015 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Homegrown NC Women Preaching Festival, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Meinrad Project Asheville- Cancelled, 2011 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 2)
  - Homegrown Organizing, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - WW, 2012-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Duke Div Women's Ctr, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Jill Raitt & Serene Jones, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - 40th Ann. of Ordination of Episc. Women, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Rebecca Jones Truthy Writing, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Stu Horwitz, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - NCCC - critical issues seminar, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Margaret Henderson Divine Alters, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - JS- Reading Flying, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Anita & Sherylyn Soul Circle: Longing for Earth-Cancelled, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - WW-2, 2012-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Consider the Conservation, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Labyrinth Binkley, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Grandmothers, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Japanese Tea Spring, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Duke Chapel Labyrinth, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Carol Henderson, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Sue Sneddon, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Betty Wolfe Sleep, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Feminism & Faith, 2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - WW, 2012-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Interfaith, 2012-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Quiet Day- Cancelled, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Harvesting Our Stories, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Talking Taboo Lunch, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Women and Money, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Ann Koppelman Camp New Hope Council of All Beings, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 3)
  - Homegrown: Women Preaching Festival, 2009-2015 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - JS speaking at Duke Div Women's Ctr., 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Fall WW, 2011-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Continuing Conversation, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Jean O'Barr w/Sallie Bingham Center, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Art of Aging - Elder Lyndall Hare, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Community Conversation, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Marcia Herman Sipping My Garden, 2013-08-05 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Teleconference with Julie Alexander, 2013-06-26 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - May WW 2013, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - WATER teleconference, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Anita McLeod, Pat Webster, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Continuing the Conversation - Film, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Japanese Tea, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - JS on the State of Thing, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Priscilla Stuckey, 2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Kathy Rudy's class, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Harvesting- Continuing Group, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - EOL, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - EOL Folder JS, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Carol Henderson, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Duke Labyrinth, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Jill Raitt Lecture & Sarah Azaransky's, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Across the Threshold Duke Dance, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Sue Sneddon, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Betty Wolfe Feldenkrais, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Enneagram, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)
  - Jan. WW 2013, 2012-2013 (Box Acc. 18/116: Box 4)